{
  "exam": [
    {
      "question": "What is the primary focus of XinFin as a blockchain technology company?",
      "choices": ["Developing video games", 
      "Providing blockchain solutions for businesses and institutions", 
      "Cryptocurrency mining", 
      "Social media platform development."],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the main purposes of XDC within the XinFin ecosystem?",
      "choices": ["Serving coffee to users",
      "Enabling interstellar travel", 
      "Facilitating transactions on the XinFin blockchain and various network functions",
      "Growing vegetables"],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "What did XinFin develop to host its XDC cryptocurrency after its initial launch on Ethereum?",
      "choices": ["XDC Market",
      "XDC Explorer", 
      "XDC Network",
      "XDC Exchange"],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of blockchain is the XDC Network, and why is it called a \"hybrid\" blockchain?",
      "choices": ["Public blockchain with unlimited transparency",
      "Private blockchain with high security",
      "Hybrid blockchain combining features of both public and private blockchains",
      "Hybrid blockchain combining features of Bitcoin and Ethereum"],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the primary purpose of the XDC Network, as described in the text?",
      "choices": ["Trade finance and payments, with a focus on global trade operations",
      "Providing blockchain solutions for individuals",
      "Developing video games",
      "Building social media platforms"],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "How can the XDC Network benefit enterprises engaged in international trade?",
      "choices": ["By increasing settlement times",
      "By adding more intermediaries",
      "By reducing settlement times and the need for intermediaries",
      "By increasing paperwork in cross-border transactions"],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the term \"interoperability\" mean in the context of the XDC Network for enterprises?",
      "choices": ["The ability to communicate only with other XDC networks",
      "The ability to integrate with current infrastructure for a smoother transition to blockchain technology",
      "Incompatibility with existing systems",
      "Limited connectivity with other blockchains"],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the use of blockchain technology on the XDC Network reduce in industries where data accuracy and integrity are critical?",
      "choices": ["Data accuracy",
      "Data volume",
      "Risk of fraud, errors, and data manipulation",
      "Operational efficiency."],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "What is one of the key advantages of the XDC Network in terms of scalability for enterprises?",
      "choices": ["It's not suitable for businesses with expanding operations",
      "It can only handle a small volume of transactions",
      "It's designed to handle a high volume of transactions efficiently",
      "It has no impact on transaction volume."],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of blockchain components are combined in the XDC Network's architecture?",
      "choices": ["Public and private chains",
      "Public and consortium chains",
      "Private and permissioned chains",
      "Public and federated chains."],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the main benefit of a hybrid blockchain's combination of public and private features?",
      "choices": ["It offers maximum privacy with no verifiability.",
      "It ensures that every user's identity is completely hidden.",
      "It combines the benefits of both public and private blockchains, offering security, transparency, and controlled access.",
      "It only benefits large organisations with no need for public interactions."],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "How are delegates in XDPoS elected to validate transactions and create new blocks?",
      "choices": ["By random selection",
      "By government appointment",
      "Based on community voting",
      "By the highest stake in XDC tokens"],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
    "question": "What is a Hybrid Blockchain and what does it combine from private and public blockchains?",
      "choices": ["Hybrid Blockchain combines private and public blockchains and offers only public access.",
      "A Hybrid Blockchain combines private and public blockchains and offers controlled access and freedom",
      "A Hybrid Blockchain combines private and public blockchains and is entirely private.",
      " Hybrid Blockchain combines private and public blockchains but offers no control over data access."],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "How does the XDC Delegated Proof-of-Stake (XDPoS) consensus address scalability challenges in blockchain platforms?",
        "choices": ["By using a centralized network administrator.",
        "By increasing transaction costs.",
        "By employing a 108-Masternode system.",
        "By offering complete anonymity."],
        "answer": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the role of a nominator in XDPoS?",
          "choices": ["A nominator is a network administrator.",
          "A nominator is responsible for producing and validating blocks.",
          "A nominator is a coin holder who stakes or delegates their coins to one or more validators.",
          "A nominator is a validator."],
          "answer": 3
        },
        {"question": "How often can a single nominator vote for a validator in XDPoS?",
            "choices": [" Once every two epochs.",
            "Once every epoch.",
            "Once every withdrawal period.",
            "Only once in their lifetime."],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {"question": "What is the role of Masternodes in the XDC Network?",
          "choices": ["Masternodes process transactions but don't require any XDC tokens as collateral.",
          "Masternodes validate transactions and govern the network's security.",
          "Masternodes are only responsible for storing blockchain data.",
          "Masternodes create new XDC tokens."],
          "answer": 2
        },
        {"question": "How do Full Nodes contribute to the XDC Network?",
        "choices": ["Full Nodes process transactions and reach consensus.",
        "Full Nodes require collateral stakes to participate.",
        "Full Nodes help distribute information across the network and store blockchain data.",
        "Full Nodes create new blocks."],
        "answer": 3
      },
      {"question": "What happens if a proposal in the XDC Network passes a certain threshold of approval?",
        "choices": ["It gets automatically implemented without any further steps.",
        "It becomes part of the XDC Network's rules and is implemented by developers.",
        "It is rejected, and no further action is taken.",
        "It remains pending indefinitely."],
        "answer": 2
      }

  ]
  }
